Stephen Pedrosa Eilert

Cellphone: +1 (669) 226-7520

Email: stephen.eilert@hpe.com
Github: github.com/outworlder

Summary

Sofware developer with 13 years of experience in a variety of projects for national and international customers. Experience with the full software development lifecycle, from requirements, design, development, testing, deployment and system administration. Highly motivated by projects that challenge the technological status-quo. Somewhat paradoxically, likes to work closer to the machine, but also at the high levels of abstraction provided by functional languages. Follows with interest new technology developments, and will learn interesting technologies even when they are not directly relevant to the current work.

Education

• BSc. Computer Science, Universidade Federal do Ceará, 2008.

Skills

- Networking: OpenFlow, OpenVSwitch, Openstack Neutron
- Cloud: HPE Helion, AWS, Docker
- Oracle Technologies: (Java Platform including J2SE, JEE and J2ME)
- Microsoft Technologies: (.NET Framework, API Win32, SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, PowerShell)
- Extensive Linux knowledge. Some experience with other unix platforms such as NetBSD.
- Programming Languages: Python, Go, C, C++, Java, C#, Javascript, Ruby, Lua, Objective-C, Scheme, Clojure
- Source Control: Git, Mercurial, SVN
- Misc Tools: Ansible, HP LoadRunner, Enterprise Architect, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, Ant, Maven, Gradle, debuggers and profilers (language/platform specific), unit and integration tests (CruiseControl, Luntbuild, RSpec, autotest, TravisCI, Jenkins), XCode
- Database Management Systems: PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL
- NoSQL databases: MongoDB, Cassandra, Redis, Memcachedb
- Mobile Development: some Android, heavy focus on iOS
- Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Backbone.js

Stephen Pedrosa Eilert

Spoken Languages

- English (Advanced)
- Portuguese (Native)

Certifications

- Sun Certified Java Programmer SCJP 5.0
- Cambridge FSOL FCE University of Cambridge

Professional Experience

1. Hewlett Packard Enterprise, 2015 - Present

Systems Software Engineer. Joined the Openstack Neutron team, to work upstream. Delivered enhancements to Neutron to support VMWare ESX's distributed virtual switch (vDS). Fixed issues and was in charge of maintenance of the internal CI servers (Jenkins). Focus shifted to HP's Helion Openstack (HOS), backporting patches, fixing CI issues and adding features and bugfixes to its Ansible-based installer.

2. Hewlett-Packard, 2014 - 2015

Software engineer, working with an experienced team to develop a high-profile platform that handles printer monitoring and supplies. Technologies range from .NET desktop and web apps, printer communication protocols and single-page web applications in Javascript/Backbone.js. Emphasis on code quality, with mandatory code reviews, high code test coverage and continuous integration.

3. Instituto Atlântico, 2013 - 2014

Software developer and tech lead on contract for Hewlett-Packard.

4. Guilda (founder) / Codeminer 42, 2012 - 2013

Co-founded a company to develop Mobile (iOS and Android), C++ (with Qt) and Ruby on Rails applications for customers. Also provided consulting services and developed a cloud-based continuous integration system (currently discontinued) – one of the first in the market to use LXC containers. Acquired by Codeminer42.

5. DETRAN-CE, 2010 - 2012

Internal software development. Web systems in Ruby on Rails, consuming data from PostgreSQL, MongoDB and Cassandra. Development of a fingerprint recognition platform using libfprint, in both C and Python. Creation of a high-performance middleware application in C to broker communication between internal and external systems with the government's mainframe.

6. Instituto Atlântico, 2004 - 2009

Developer and technical leader in several projects for a variety of customers. Among them, was the development of a new banking platform in Java (J2EE) to replace the aging, mainframe-based system. Also of note was a image-based (using an optical-flow algorithm), motion detection module for a proprietary mobile operating system. Spent some time in Gibraltar with a team to finish development, deployment of the customer's new platform in Ruby on Rails, as well as measuring performance and adding a caching layer (with Memcached) so that it would support an upcoming major sporting event.

7. Media System, 2003 - 2004

Trainee. .NET desktop and mobile application development.

Last updated: September 15, 2016 http://github.com/outworlder/CV.git/